

Contacts

ADDRESS : Lausanne, Switzerland

EMAIL ☑: jeremy.zuchuat@gmail.com

PHONE : + 41 77 435 96 71

Website \oplus : jeremyzuchuat.github.io

Social (1): linkedin.com/j-zuchuat

Expertise

Data analytics (micro- & macroeconometrics, discrete choice analysis, machine learning)

Program evaluation

Economic modeling

Data visualization (including GIS)

Data management, big data

Programming Skills

 Stata:
 ● ● ● ● ●

 R:
 ● ● ● ●

 QGIS:
 ● ● ● ●

 Python:
 ● ● ● ○

Personal Skills

Project management, Communication, Pedagogy, Collaboration

Language

French (native), English (fluent), German (proficient)

References

Pr. Rafael Lalive (supervisor, UNIL)

Pr. Josef Zweimüller (UZH)

Pr. Mathias Thoenig, (UNIL)

Pr. Aurélien Eyquem, (UNIL)

Contacts available upon request

Hobbies

Ski(-touring), biking, running, photography

JEREMY **ZUCHUAT**

Young applied PhD economist specialized in labor market and policy evaluation, refined through policy work for Swiss public institutions. Advanced Stata and R programmer, with extensive knowledge in data analysis-management-visualisation, quantitative methods and economic modeling. Large experience in the use of Swiss adminstrative data. Quick learner with a strong analytical mindset and a good ability to work under pressure.

WORK EXPERIENCE

PhD Candidate in Labor Economics, 09.2018-06.2023 (expected),

University of Lausanne

- Wrote 4 academic papers investigating job seekers' and firms' behaviors in the Swiss labor market, as well as the impact of labor market policies and taxation on (un-)employed workers' outcomes.
- Participated in the Swiss Program for Beginning Doctoral Students in Economics at Study Center Gerzensee (GPA 5.7/6.0).
- Main teaching assistant in Applied Econometrics and Macroeconomics.

Lecturer, 02.2023-08.2023, University of Lausanne

- Teaching applied economic research to 3^d year Bachelor students (research plan definition, empirical analyses, output presentation).

Economic Consultant, 07.2020-12.2022, Centre for Applied Research

- Conducted micro-econometric analyses on the labor market outcomes of social assistance beneficiaries in the Canton de Vaud.
- Studied the macro-econometric consequences of COVID on the social assistance scheme in the Canton de Vaud.

Research assistant, 09.2016-08.2018, University of Lausanne

- Worked on labor-related topics for Pr. Rafael Lalive.
- Data management, empirical analyses and redaction of a descriptive report for a SECO mandate on Swiss job seekers' outcomes.

EDUCATION

PhD in Labor Economics, University of Lausanne, 2023 (expected)

Supervisor : Pr. Rafael Lalive

MSc in Economics, University of Lausanne, 2018, GPA 6.0/6.0

BSc in Economics, University of Lausanne, 2016, GPA 5.9/6.0

Additional training: Winter School in Data Analytics and Machine Learning (UNIFR), Discrete Choice Analysis (EPFL)

RESEARCH

- 1. How Vacancy Referrals affect Job Search: Evidence from Job Applications Data
- 2. What Drives the Decline in the Job Offer Arrival Rate? (with R. Lalive, A. Osikominu,
- L. Pesaresi & J. Zweimüller)
- 3. Commuting and Income Sorting in Fiscally Decentralized Cities (with N. Mauri)
- 4. Estimating Duration Dependence in Job Search: the Within-Estimation Duration

Presented in workshops and conferences, with international audience.

AWARDS AND HONORS

2021: Econometric Game, Amsterdam, HEC Lausanne team captain, Top 8

2018 : Prix de Faculté, HEC Lausanne, (best Master student in Economics)

2016: Prix Ernst & Young SA, HEC Lausanne (prize for excellence)

2014-2016 : Prix de la Faculté des HEC (Best Bachelor Student, $1^{\rm st}$, $2^{\rm d}$ and $3^{\rm d}$ year)